Guide to the Mary Coolidge Rentschler Collection 1793-2000 (bulk, 1875-1950) MS 2999
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Manuscripts and memorabilia
  - Subseries I.B. Mary Coolidge Rentschler (1892–1988) [MCR]
    These materials provide biographical materials necessary to construct the family tree and chronological information on the family. Box Man-14, Folder 11, contains a photographic copy of an essay written by Louise Lionberger Amory (no date) about summer vacations at the turn of the 19th century in Marion, Massachusetts, at the home of Mary Augusta Clapp Shepley (also known as Ama), Mary C. Rentschler's grandmother.
    - Legal documents, 1916-1960 (Offsite-box Man-3, Folder 20)
      1) Marriage certificate of Edwin F. Atkins Jr. and Mary C. Rentschler, 1916
      2) Marriage certificate of MCR and Gordon Sohn Rentschler, 1927
      3) Copy of MCR birth certificate, 1942
      4) Copy of GSR death certificate, [1960?]
    - Copy of Will, 1947 October 29 (Offsite-box Man-3, Folder 21)
      Copy of last will and testament of Gordon S. Rentschler, October 29, 1947 (papers came with MCR materials).
    - Certificate of free passage for Julia Shepley Coolidge, issued in Rome, Italy, 1879 May 25 (Offsite-box Ovz-2)
      Certificate of free passage (a passport) provided to Julia Shepley (Coolidge) by the Legation of the United States in Rome, Italy.
    - Correspondence, 1889 February 24-March 17 (Offsite-box Man-3, Folder 22)
      Love letters from Charles A. Coolidge Sr. to Julia S. Coolidge. Social engagement; Louis Brandeis, February 24, 1889; Mr. Olmsted, March 5, 1889; temperance, February 25, 1889; successful business, March 9, 1889.
    - Correspondence, 1889 March 19-1908 November 4 (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 1)
      Love letters from Charles A. Coolidge to Julia S. Coolidge. Implied resistance by JSC to marriage and monogamy. Various architectural projects (New York stations; Stanford University; Sanitarium). Mention of Olmsted. Prohibition and anti-temperance attitude.
    - Checks, 1898 July 12-1900 June 13 (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 2)
      Checks paid to beneficiaries of the will of James Mulligan: Lucy Hennessey, John J. McNally, and City of Boston. Signed by executors of the will E. F. Atkins and James O'Brien.
    - Diary, 1904 December 25-1906 April 15 (Offsite-box 2, Box Mem-16)
      "A Line a Day" diary.
    - Diary, 1912 (Offsite-box 2, Box Mem-18)
    - Publication, 1913 (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 3)
      "A Message to Garcia" by Elbert Hubbard. Moralizing tract on virtues of initiative and hard work vs. laziness and ineptitude.
    - Diary, 1915 (Offsite-box 2, Box Mem-19)
      Daily Reminder.
    - Diary, circa 1915 January-February (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 4)
      Social life; theatre engagements and relationship with fiance, Edwin F. Atkins.
    - Correspondence, 1916 June 7-1917 May 7 (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 5)
      Corr. from Mary C. Rentschler in Bsoton and Cuba to father and mother, Charles A. and Julia S. Coolidge. Disbelief at upcoming marriage to Edwin F. Atkins. Announcing pregnancy; desire for a boy. Political turmoil and domestic/social life of Cuba.
    - Wedding invitations, 1916 June 7 (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 6)
      Invitations to the wedding of Mary C. Rentschler to Edwin F. Atkins.
    - Diary, 1916 June 7-1917 March 25 (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 7)
      Honeymoon in the USA. Social life in Cuba interwoven with political turmoil and violence. Reports of burned sugarcane crops and rebel attacks.
    - Correspondence and photograph, 1917 Januar 28 (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 8)
      Letter and photograph from Isabel Coolidge in Vosges, France, to her sister, Mary C. Rentschler (in the USA?). IC is a nurse. CHristmas in WWI French hospital. The party was courtesy of MCR. Photograph of the Christmas tree.
    - Correspondence, 1917 March (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 9)
      Letter from Mary C. Rentschler to her father, Charles A. Coolidge, re: political turmoil in Cuba. Kidnapping of Mrs. Van Petten (sp?). (See diary in Box 4, Folder 7, for more on this.)
    - Diary and cartoon, 1917 March 27-April 17 (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 10)
      Diary of Mary C. Rentschler in Cuba. Sugarcane production. Political turmoil: reports of murder and rebels threatening to burn cane crops if they are not paid ransom money. Mention of Edwin F. Atkins Sr., Edwin F. Atkins Jr., Mr. Hughes. Cartoon.
    - Correspondence, 1917 July 31-1918 July 5 (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 11)
      Correspondence from Edwin F. Atkins Jr. and Mary C. Rentschler to Edwin F. Atkins and Katherine W. Atkins. EFA and MCR report on army life -- as soldier and army wife. Food, sickness -- EFA tonsils removed. Sympathetic attitude of female Dr. to child rearing.
    - Correspondence, 1917 October 5 (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 12)
      Letter from ? to Llewellyn F. Hughes re: arranging a tennis party at Soledad?
    - Correspondence, circa 1918-1921 (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 13)
      Correspondence from Edwin F. Atkins Jr., in signal corps, to mother re: army politics; wishing for transferral; tonsils to be removed; missing new baby. Correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler in Cuba to Katherin Atkins re: social life; sugar industry; Buzzards Bay affair.
    - Correspondence, 1923 January 11-12 (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 14)
      Correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler, Edwin F. Atkins III, and David C. Atkins, to Julia C. Coolidge just before the fatal plane crash. MCR describes the rigors of traveling with two young sons. Sightseeing in Washington, D.C. Sons letters to their grandmother.
    - Correspondence, 1923 January 11-March 9 (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 15)
      Condolence letters to Charles A. Coolidge upon fatal plane crash of son-in-law, Edwin F. Atkins Jr., and grandsons, Edwin F. Atkins III and David C. Atkins.
    - Correspondence, 1923 August 8-1963 August 30 (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 16)
      Diary and correspondence of B. E. McLaughlin, nanny to Faith A. Witter. Faith aged 9 months to 4 years. Excellent diary of infant growth, eating habits, learning to walk age 18 months. Letter detailing chronology of events re: Atkins family.
    - Correspondence, 1923 October 20-1924 December 30 (Offsite-box Man-4, Folder 17)
      General correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler in Belmont, Massachusetts, to Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City. (Stationery with black border; MCR in mourning.) Social news. Thank-yous for gifts. MCR grateful to GSR for speaking of former husband Edwin F. Atkins Jr.
    - Correspondence, 1925 January 7-December 30 (Offsite-box Man-5, Folder 1)
      General correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler in Massachusetts to Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City, London, and Paris. (Stationery with black border; MCR in mourning.) Social news: Faith Witter vis-a-vis GSR; GSR vaccination against typhoid; ducking hunting in Virginia. MCR botany class.
    - Correspondence, 1925 June 19 (Offsite-box Man-5, Folder 2)
      Letter from Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City to Mary C. Rentschler in Belmont, Massachusetts. Social news. Princeton commencement dinner with Charles Mitchell (president of NCB of New York) and Harriman, discussion re: Russian Bolsheviks.
    - Correspondence, 1925 August 20-October 19 (Offsite-box Man-5, Folder 3)
      Gordon S. Rentschler to Mary C. Rentschler. GSR on business trip around Europe. Wonderful descriptions of places, foreign dignitaries, bankers. Luxury bathroom in Barcelona; motoring around Lake Como; Parisian nightlife; love of UK; gossip re: Rasputin.
    - Correspondence, 1925 November 1-1927 March 12 (Offsite-box Man-5, Folder 4)
      Correspondence from Gordon S. Rentschler and Alison Coolidge to Mary C. Rentschler, includes descriptions of business trips to South & Midwest; attitudes to Civil War, sensitive comment -- E. F. Atkins Jr. would be pround of Faith; mention of Brady, Chapin, Koniger.
    - Correspondence, 1926 January 28-May 21 (Offsite-box Man-5, Folder 5)
      Correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler in Cienfuegos, Cuba, to Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City. Daily life in Cuba; politics, hardships for general population, sugarcane industry, guao [guano?] poisoning?, presents for Faith A. Witter, social engagements, illness, Llewellyn Hughes.
    - Correspondence, circa 1926 January-May (Offsite-box Man-5, Folder 6)
      Tender love letters from Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City and Cuba to Mary C. Rentschler in Cuba. GSR opinions on world politics & economics. Suggestions to MCR re: Cuban Public Works Projects. Hectic social life. Redecoration of 933 5th Avenue, New York City.
    - Correspondence, 1926 May 21-1928 January 22 (Offsite-box Man-5, Folder 7)
      Correspondence from Gordon S. Rentschler on trip to Europe to Mary C. Rentschler and Charles A. Coolidge in Massachusetts. Abstract of log from Atlantic crossing. Optimistic views of world affairs (1926 Sunday). Thank you to CAC. Condolence re: E. F. Atkins.
    - Correspondence, 1926 May 24-October 14 (Offsite-box Man-5, Folder 8)
      Correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler in Belmont, Massachusetts, to Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City. Daily life; social engagements; arrangements to see each other; explosion in MCR's chemistry class (July 28, 1926); sudden death of Ralph Crewes; Faith A. Witter drawing (September 17, 1926).
    - Correspondence, 1926 October 15-December 28 (Offsite-box Man-6, Folder 1)
      Correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler in Massachusetts to Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City. Daily life; social engagements; Faith Witter's progress; thank-yous for gifts from GSR. Watching "Soledad movies" (November 18, 1926). Asks if GSR involved in political appointment of Schumanan (sp?).
    - Correspondence, 1927 January 8-February 28 (Offsite-box Man-6, Folder 2)
      Correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler in Massachusetts and Cuba to Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City. Daily life of social engagments. MCR recuperating after he appendectomy. Thank-yous for constant gifts of chocolates and flowers from GSR.
    - Correspondence, 1927 February 19-March 9 (Offsite-box Man-6, Folder 3)
      Love letters from Gordon S. Rentschler to Mary C. Rentschler in Cuba. Written while traveling north from Cuba to New York City. Writes of the joy her love has brought him.
    - Correspondence, 1927 February 26-July 8 (Offsite-box Man-6, Folder 4)
      Correspondence from Helen R. Waldon and Sidney D. Waldon. Letters of utter devotion and joy from HRW to her brother, Gordon S. Rentschler, upon his betrothal to MCR. Incredible letter from SDW to GSR re: SDW's love for HRW and request for permission to marry her.
    - Correspondence, 1927 March 1-14 (Offsite-box Man-6, Folder 5)
      Love letters from Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City to Mary C. Rentschler in Cienfuegos, Cuba. Longs for MCR (March 11). Social life in New York City. Work at the bank--locating new branches in Queens (March 5). Eminent Dutch banker dr. Vissemig? (March 11).
    - Correspondence, 1927 March 1-31 (Offsite-box Man-6, Folder 6)
      Joyous, teasing love letters from Mary C. Rentschler to Gordon S. Rentschler. Life in Cuba. Joy breaking news of their betrothal. Advantages of being a man (March 29). Unlikely social gatherings (March 8); GSR with two mothers-in-law (March 30). Joyce Hughes death (March 2).
    - Correspondence, 1927 March 8-April 10 (Offsite-box Man-6, Folder 7)
      Letters of congratulations to Mary C. Rentschler on betrothal: Julia S. Coolidge, Helen R. Waldon, Julia C. Deane & telegram from Atkins. Letters from JSC re: death of Joyce Hughes. Faith Witter's excitement to see her mother, from nanny C. Holmes.
    - Correspondence, 1927 March 15-25 (Offsite-box Man-6, Folder 8)
      Passionate love letters from Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City to Mary C. Rentschler in Cuba. Full desire for MCR. Dinner with Kerensky (March 25). Walking downtown to the bank. Life at the bank. Watching the moon rise over Central Park (March 19).
    - Correspondence, 1927 March 26-31 (Offsite-box Man-7, Folder 1)
      Passionate love letters from Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City to Mary C. Rentschler in Cuba. Arrangements for rendezvous (March 26). Social life in New York City. High-powered dinner (March 29).
    - Correspondence, 1927 April 1-16 (Offsite-box Man-7, Folder 2)
      Passionate love letters from Gordon S. Rentschler in New YOrk City to Mary C. Rentschler. Breaking news of engagement to family; meeting CAC to ask for MCR's hand; warm reception for GSR at Coolidge's (April 2-3); MCR resembles GSR's mother (April 8); Mrs. G. Cleveland (April 16?).
    - Correspondence, 1927 April 1-27 (Offsite-box Man-7, Folder 3)
      Correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler in Cuba and Massachusetts to Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City. Joy at breaking news of their betrothal (April 2). Engagement ring (April 27). Life in cuba: running plantation, sewing classes. Mr. Ford in accident (April 4). Hilarious pork indigestion story (April 4).
    - Correspondence, 1927 April 1-27 (Offsite-box Man-7, Folder 4)
      Telegrams of congratulation to Gordon S. Rentschler upon news of his engagement to Mary C. Rentschler.
    - Correspondence, 1927 April 2-17 (Offsite-box Man-7, Folder 5)
      Letters of congratulation to Gordon S. Rentschler from family and friends upon the news of his engagement to Mary C. Rentschler (April 1-17).
    - Correspondence, 1927 April 2-23 (Offsite-box Man-7, Folder 6)
      Letters of congratulation to Mary C. Rentschler from close family and friends upon the news of her engagement to Gordon S. Rentschler.
    - Correspondence, 1927 April 17-June 13 (Offsite-box Man-7, Folder 7)
      Letters of congratulation from family and friends of Gordon S. Rentschler upon the news of his engagement to Mary C. Rentschler.
    - Correspondence, 1927 April 19-May 14 (Offsite-box Man-7, Folder 8)
      Correspondence from Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City to Mary C. Rentschler in Belmont, Massachusetts, prior to their marriage. Wedding arrangements and arrangements to meet. Social life, including dinner with Baruch and Mrs. Woodrow Wilson? (May 3); dinner with G. Buckly (May 13).
    - Correspondence, 1927 April 25-29 (Offsite-box Man-7, Folder 9)
      News clippings of the engagement of Mary C. Rentschler and Gordon S. Rentschler.
    - Correspondence, 1927 May 1-June 15 (Offsite-box Man-8, Folder 1)
      Letters of congratulation from friends to Gordon S. Rentschler upon the news of his engagement to Mary C. Rentschler.
    - Correspondence, 1927 May 2-31 (Offsite-box Man-8, Folder 2)
      Correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler in Belmont, Massachusetts, to Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City. Arrangements for imminent betrothal and honeymoon. Moving her belongings to New York City. MCR chemistry classes.
    - Correspondence, 1927 May 17-28 (Offsite-box Man-8, Folder 3)
      Correspondence from Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City to Mary C. Rentschler in Belmont, Massachusetts. Daily social and business life. Litany of people, including Bernard Baruch (May 19). Prize fight in Philadelphia (May 19). Parties, many with Charles Mitchell, NCB bank colleague.
    - Correspondence, 1927 June 1-22 (Offsite-box Man-8, Folder 4)
      Love letters from Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City to Mary C. Rentschler in Massachusetts and Colorado. Constantly waiting for her letters. Endless dinner parties and names. Dinner at Ritz -- saw Charlie Chaplin. Jerome N. Bonapart (June 8). Princeton reunion (June 17-20).
    - Correspondence, 1927 June 1-July 2 (Offsite-box Man-8, Folder 5)
      Correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler in Colorado to Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City & Ohio prior to GSR's traveling to Colorado for wedding. Beautiful descriptions of landscape, hiking, and riding. Faith A. Witter learning to ride (June 29). Isabel Coolidge marital problems (June 18).
    - Correspondence, 1927 June 15-July 17 (Offsite-box Man-8, Folder 6)
      Correspondence from Helen Claflin, Julia S. Coolidge, and Charles A. Coolidge, to Mary C. Rentschler on MCR's impending marriage. Joy at upcoming wedding mixed with sadness of parents being unable to attend.
    - Correspondence, 1927 June 23-July 10 (Offsite-box Man-8, Folder 7)
      Love letters from Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City and Ohio to Mary C. Rentschler in Colorado, just prior to their marriage. GSR explains that his middle name honors his father's business partner Henry Sohn (June 25). Work at the bank. Visiting dignitaries.
    - Correspondence, circa 1927 June-July? (Offsite-box Man-8, Folder 8)
      Letter from Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City to Katherine W. Atkins in Massachusetts. Reiterates MCR's and GSR's continued love for KWA in light of imminent marriage. Travel arrangements to Colorado for the wedding.
    - Correspondence, 1927 July 3-20 (Offsite-box Man-9, Folder 1)
      Correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler in Colorado to Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City and Colorado just prior to their marriage. Wedding arrangements and marriage issues re: Faith Witter.
    - Correspondence, 1927 July 11-21 (Offsite-box Man-9, Folder 2)
      Love letters from Gordon S. Rentschler in New York City and Colorado to Mary C. Rentschler in Colorado just prior to their marriage. Inscribed ring: GSR-MCA (July 14). GSR visit with Coolidges (July 16). (Honeymoon flyer from the Redstone Club removed to Oversize Box 3.)
    - Flyer from the Redstone Inn, Colorado, circa 1927 (Offsite-box Ovz-3)
      Flyer from The Redstone Inn, Redstone, Colorado (where Gordon S. Rentschler and Mary C. Rentschler stayed on their honeymoon?).
    - Correspondence, 1927 July 18-August 30 (Offsite-box Man-9, Folder 3)
      Letters of congratulation to Gordon S. Rentschler upon his marriage to Mary C. Rentschler. Letters are from business (Midwest) and personal friends.
    - Invitation, 1927 July (Offsite-box Man-9, Folder 4)
      Invitation to the wedding of Mary C. Rentschler and Gordon S. Rentschler in Denver, Colorado.
    - Wedding list, 1927 July (Offsite-box Man-9, Folder 5)
      Wedding list for the wedding of Mary C. Rentschler and Gordon S. Rentschler in Denver, Colorado.
    - Wedding guest book, 1927 (Offsite-box 2, Box Mem-22)
      Wedding guest book for the wedding of Mary C. Rentschler and Gordon S. Rentschler in Denver, Colorado.
    - Marriage program, 1927 July 23 (Offsite-box Man-9, Folder 6)
      Bound marriage service of Gordon S. Rentschler and Mary C. Rentschler, St. John's Cathedral, Denver, Colorado.
    - Telegram, 1927 July 23-August 23 (Offsite-box Man-9, Folder 7)
      Telegrams of congratulation to Gordon S. Rentschler and Mary C. Rentschler upon their marriage.
    - Receipt / invoice, 1927 September 14 (Offsite-box Man-9, Folder 8)
      Receipt or invoice to Mary C. Rentschler probably for clothing worn during her wedding ceremonies.
    - Correspondence, circa 1927 (Offsite-box Man-9, Folder 9)
      General correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler in Cuba to her daughter, Faith A. Witter, in Massachusetts.
    - Correspondence, 1927 April 11-1939 February 9 (Offsite-box Man-9, Folder 10)
      Correspondence between Mary C. Rentschler and her daughter, Faith A. Witter. Mainly from FAW to MCR, detailing her school and social life.
    - Correspondence, circa 1927-1929 (Offsite-box Man-9, Folder 11)
      Fabulous letters from Mary C. Rentschler in Cuba, New York City, and Long Island, mainly to Katherine W. Atkins. Social and economic lives of rich; parties; spoiled Phoebe; relationship with Faith; imminent Stock Market Crash; moving letter re: dead EFA Jr. to EFA Sr.
    - Correspondence, 1927 July 15-1938 June 27 (Offsite-box Man-9, Folder 12)
      Correspondence from Julia C. Deane in Massachusetts to her sister, Mary C. Rentschler, in New York City and Long Island. Deane and Rentschler private lives: health, financial worries, including Supreme Court rulings on Dick Whitney and Charlie Mitchell (March 8, 1938). Frederick on verge of breakdown? (June 27, 1938).
    - Correspondence, 1928 August 28-September 4 (Offsite-box Man-9, Folder 13)
      Letters from Nancy Goode McLaughlin, Faith A. Witter's nanny, to Mary C. Rentschler. McL first describes missing Faith, who is with her mother (in Ohio?), and then writes from Nantucket in late summer, where she is looking after Faith on vacation.
    - Correspondence, 1929 February 2-1935 November 28 (Offsite-box Man-10, Folder 1)
      Correspondence and telegram mainly from Julia S. Coolidge to daughter Mary C. Rentschler. Daily lives at onset of Depression; distress of GSR in D.C. hearings (March 8, 1933); health; congratulations from Charles A. Coolidge at birth of Susan R. Witter; family gatherings.
    - Correspondence, 1929 April-1931 September (Offsite-box Man-10, Folder 2)
      Miscellaneous correspondence from Helen R. Waldon, Sidney D. Waldon, Mary C. Rentschler, and Mary Schwab, to Gordon S. Rentschler. Series of letters re: HRW's stillbirth of a baby boy. Congratulations on GSR as NCB President. MS on status of lost heirloom. SRW re: horse feed costs.
    - Correspondence / cartoon, 1929 May 9 (Offsite-box Man-10, Folder 3)
      Letter from William A. Ireland to Mary C. Rentschler. Humorous, illustrated letter, thanking MCR and Gordon S. Rentschler for a wonderful dinner party.
    - Correspondence, 1929 July 11-1937 August 23 (Offsite-box Man-10, Folder 4)
      Miscellaneous correspondence from Gordon S. Rentschler to Mary C. Rentschler. Response to MCR's letter of January 16, 1932 re: Phoebe shooting fish. Susan R. Witer (September 18, 1935). Hamilton Farm and GAR Jr. building a car (August 23, 1937). New Year's Eve letters from GSR & MCR to CAC Sr.
    - Correspondence, 1929 July 19-22 (Offsite-box Man-10, Folder 5)
      Correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler to Gordon S. Rentschler. Embarking on a summer vaction to Marion, Massachusetts. Descriptions of happy children on vacation.
    - Correspondence and hair, 1930 May 14-1931 June 24 (Offsite-box Man-10, Folder 6)
      Locks of hair from Phoebe R. Stanton and Mary R. Lowrey. Poem by Mrs. Talbott Sr. about three little piggies (i.e., the children).
    - Correspondence, circa 1931? (Offsite-box Man-10, Folder 7)
      Miscellaneous social correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler to Katherine W. Atkins, includes MCR sadness after death of sons and husband (Saturday, Book Cadillac Hotel, Detroit). Relationship between granddaughter (Faith Witter) & stepfather (GSR) vis-a-vis KWA (July 10).
    - Correspondence, 1932 January 8-1933 November 25 (Offsite-box Man-10, Folder 8)
      Social correspondence from Helen R. Waldon and Mary C. Rentschler to Gordon S. Rentschler. HRW: letters of adoration; treasury bonds (June 8, 1932); Hamilton Farm news (January 17, 1933); MCR: vacation stories, including Phoebe fishing (January 16, 1932). GSR letter re: Hoover, Mary Pickford?
    - Correspondence, circa 1932-1940 (Offsite-box Man-10, Folder 9)
      Correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler to Katherine W. Atkins. Private & public lives: MCR pregnancy, CAC death, Atkins family finances, attitudes re: social etiquette & chaperoning Faith. GSR banking turmoil & Senate hearings: sale of Trinidad plantation.
    - Correspondence, 1933 February 9; 1935 January 14 (Offsite-box Man-10, Folder 10)
      Correspondence from Mary C. Rentschler to her father, Charles A. Coolidge Sr. 1st letter: thank you re: book; details of completion of CAC chapel (February 9, 1933). 2nd letter: thank you re: paint set; Gordon S. Rentschler on witness stand re: Management Fund (January 14, 1935).
    - Correspondence, 1933 March 29-April 7 (Offsite-box Man-10, Folder 11)
      Letters and a telegram of congratulations to Mary C. Rentschler and Gordon S. Rentschler on the birth of Susan R. Witter (March 28, 1933). Letter from SRW's namesake, Mommer Brant.